

Phone: +91-7878217377

Email:

kishanpanchal3652@gmail.com

Linked In: kishan-panchal22

Passport Number: V0709993

Summary

An Export Professional with demonstrated work history Presently Designated as Assistant Export Manager, having experience of more than 6.5 years in Managing and developing International Business. Actively looking for an Opportunity to work with a Growing Organization where I can utilize my experience & Skills and work towards company as well as personal growth. In Past Assignments Worked with Textile Industry and Food & FMCG Industry.

Work Experience

Line O Matic Graphic Industries, Ahmedabad. (Manufacturer & Exporter of Paper Converting machinery & Automatic Exercise Book machine.)

Industry: Engineering

Assistant Export Manager - 10/2022 to Present.

- Generating business from Europe & Africa Region
- Identify new business opportunities and develop the business through existing clients.
- Clear understanding of client needs, pressure points, and workout best solution.
- Proposal preparation to negotiation and order finalization.
- Coordination for L/C, all other pre- and post-shipment documents, following realization of payment in Bank, etc.
- Maintaining good relation with customer for long and strong business relationship.
- Keep a check on smooth operation of logistics and export documentation.
- International travelling for business generation.
- Maintaining MIS sales report.

Viasola Private Limited, Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India. (Merchant Exporter)

Industry: Food & FMCG

Export Manager - 04/2021 to 10/2022. Export Executive – 01/2019 to 03/2021

- International Marketing & Sales (Region; Africa, USA, Canada) through Email & WhatsApp.
- Maintaining good relation with Existing customer for long and strong business relationship.
- Data Analysis of Export Data.
- Market Research and Development.
- Data Collection through Google & Other Medium.
- Inquiry/Lead Generation
- Domestic Procurement/Sourcing for Export Order.
- Export Costing.
- End to End Shipment Planning & Freight Negotiation.

- End to End Logistic and Supply chain Management.
- Warehouse Management.
- Inventory Management (Excel Mode)
- Export Documentation (Pre- shipment & Post-Shipment)
- Forex Banking Work
- Monthly MIS Sales Report.
- E-waybill Generation.
- End to End Coordination with team, Supplier, Customer, Shipping line, CHA, Forwarder, Government Bodies, Export Inspection Council, Inspection Companies, ECGC, DGFT, FSSAI, Spices Board, Tea Board, Coffee Board, APEDA, FIEO, Testing Laboratories and any other bodies as and when required.
- Monthly Return Filing & Yearly Renewal of Memberships.
- Cross Border Trade/ Third Country Export.
- International Travelling for Business Generation.
- 24 X 7 Customer Support.

Exhibited In

- 1) SIAL 2021-22 Pragati Maidan, Delhi, India Viasola Private Limited (09th December to 11th December 2021)
- 2) BEST OF INDIA EXPO 2022 ICCB, Dhaka, Bangladesh Viasola Private Limited. (23rd June to 25th June 2022)

Accomplishments

- Successfully set up new customers & generated Business from USA, Canada & Australia based customers.
- Experienced in Handling more than 25 containers in single day- End to End Process.
- Well versed with the cross border trade shipments & Its Procedures.

Sintex industries limited (YARN DIVISION- HO), Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India.

Industry: Textile Industry – Yarn Manufacturing

Commercial Executive - Export Documentation - 07/2016 to 09/2018

- Export Documentation (Pre- shipment & Post-Shipment)
- Monthly MIS Sales Report (Department Wise)
- End to End Coordination with team, Customer, Shipping line, CHA, Forwarder, Government Bodies, Export Inspection Council & any other bodies as and when required.
- Out Side Work as and when required.
- Managing 2 person team by self and achieve required output in timely manner.
- 24 X 7 Customer Support.

Certifications

- Certificate Course in Advance Excel by SEDEK, Government of India
- Customs Clearance Program organized by AMA (Ahmedabad Management Association)
- Entrepreneurship Development Program organized by "Centre for Entrepreneurship Management" (CED), Gandhinagar, Gujarat, India.
- Participated in the ACFI virtual Basic Cargo Awareness Program (BCAP) organized by Air Cargo Forum India
- Export import management course from JBS academy, Ahmedabad.
- Export import management course from AMA (Ahmedabad Management Association)

Skills

- International Marketing & Sales
- Leadership Skills
- Business Development
- Excellent Communication
- Negotiation Skills
- Team Management
- Effective Email Writing

Languages

- Gujarati Fluent
- Hindi Fluent
- · English Fluent

Software

- Microsoft Office
- Advance Excel
- Tally
- B2B & B2C platforms
- ERP System

Education summary

- M.B.A (Operation Management) Jaipur national university (Distance Learning) (2015-2017) (First Class)
- B.B.A (Marketing Management) GLS institute of business administration (2012-2015) (First Class)
- Higher Secondary School Education
 Gujarat Board (2011-2012) (80.28%)
- Secondary School Education Gujarat Board (2009-2010) (78.15%)

Salary Information

- Current CTC: INR 7.00 Lacs/ Annum
- Expected Salary: Same as Present

Personal Details

- Date of Birth: 22nd November 1994
- Present Address: 3, Pratik tenements, part-2, Near India colony, Thakkar nagar, Ahmedabad-382350.
- State: Gujarat
- Country: India
- Nationality: Indian

Declaration

I hereby declare that the above-furnished information is true to the best of my knowledge.

Date: 01.02.2023 Place: Ahmedabad